Guide to the First Congregational Church of Portland records 1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Images, 1857-2013; Series V
  - Performing and visual arts, Subseries 11
    - "Antigone", 1965 April 3 (Box-folder 107/26)
    - Artreach members and exhibits, 1973-2007 (Box-folder 107/27)
    - Artreach exhibits, 1990 (Box-folder 107/28)
    - Artreach exhibit of handwork and church members' collections, 1990 May (Box-folder 108/1)
    - Artreach exhibit and Washington County Chorale performance, 1990 June (Box-folder 108/2)
    - Artreach exhibit and Washington County Chorale performance (negatives), 1990 June (Box-folder 156/9)
    - Portraits and profiles of actors in "John Brown's Body", 1982 (Box-folder 108/3)
    - Group photo of cast members in "John Brown's Body", 1982 (Box-folder 108/4)
    - "Mr. Mergenthwirker's Lobblies", 1960 December 2 (Box-folder 108/5)
    - "Noye's Fludde", 1975 April (Box-folder 108/6)
    - "Noye's Fludde", 1985 (Box-folder 108/7)
    - Park Block Revels, 1974-circa 1993 (Box-folder 108/8)
    - "Spark in Judea", 1958 April 9 (Box-folder 108/9)
    - "Our Town", 1976 April-May (Box-folder 108/10)
    - "The Staring Match", 1959 June 5-6 (Box-folder 108/11)
    - "The Tavern", 1952 May (Box-folder 108/12)
    - "The Vigil", 1959 March (Box-folder 108/13)
    - "While It Was Still Dark", 1957 (Box-folder 108/14)
    - "The Willow Plate", 1951 October (Box-folder 108/15)
      Might also include images from an October 1958 performance.
    - "The Windmills of Holland", 1922 March 21 (Box-folder 108/16)
    - Cast of unidentified production, circa 1925 (Box-folder 108/17)
    - Unidentified productions, circa 1950-1980 (Box-folder 108/18)
    - Unidentified productions, circa 1955 (Box-folder 108/19)
    - Unidentified productions, 1986; undated (Box-folder 108/20)
  - Missionary work, Subseries 12
    - Frances Clapp in Japan, 1928-1939; undated (Box-folder 108/21)
    - Reverend Edwin D. Kellogg with other missionaries and theological students at Shadown, China, circa 1910 (Box-folder 108/22)
  - Social action, Subseries 13
    - Mission teachers and pupils, circa 1900 (Box-folder 108/23)
    - Cuban refugee project, 1963 (Box-folder 108/24)
    - Eat Pye, 2001 (Box-folder 109/1)
    - Gay Pride parades, 2000-2007 (Box-folder 109/2)
    - Habitat for Humanity work, 2004 (Box-folder 109/3)
    - First Congregational unit of Red Cross sewing, 1945 (Box-folder 109/4)
    - Women In Community Service (WICS) - Life Skills graduation luncheon, 2001 November 3 (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Anniversary celebrations, Subseries 14
    - 90th anniversary dinner, 1941 (Box-folder 109/6)
    - Centennial anniversary celebration, 1951 (Box-folder 109/7)
    - Reverend Raymond Walker at 110th anniversary celebration, 1961 (Box-folder 109/8)
    - 119th anniversary celebration, 1970 (Box-folder 109/9)
    - 120th anniversary celebration, 1971 (Box-folder 109/10)
    - 123rd anniversary celebration, 1974 (Box-folder 109/11)
    - 125th anniversary celebration, 1976 (Box-folder 109/12)
    - 128th anniversary celebration, 1979 (Box-folder 109/13)
    - Cake for 136th anniversary celebration, 1987 (Box-folder 109/14)
    - Anniversary celebration, circa 1988 (Box-folder 109/15)
    - 137th anniversary celebration, 1988 (Box-folder 109/16)
    - 138th anniversary celebration, 1989 (Box-folder 109/17)
    - Cake for 139th anniversary celebration, 1990 (Box-folder 109/18)
    - 140th anniversary celebration, 1991 June (Box-folder 109/19)
    - Display for 141st anniversary, 1992 June 14 (Box-folder 109/20)
    - 143rd anniversary celebration, 1994 (Box-folder 109/21)
  - Meetings, Subseries 15
    - Annual meeting, circa 1975 (Box-folder 109/22)
    - Annual meeting, 1988 (Box-folder 109/23)
    - Annual meeting, 1994 January 30 (Box-folder 109/24)
    - Companions in Christ meeting group, 2004 (Box-folder 109/25)
    - Disciples' Group meeting, circa 1988 (Box-folder 109/26)
    - Membership Commission meeting, 1989 July 12 (Box-folder 109/27)
    - Meeting, 1985 June (Box-folder 109/28)
    - Meetings, etc., 1975-2006 (Box-folder 109/29)
    - Service People meeting, circa 1945 (Box-folder 109/30)
    - Unidentified meeting, circa 1988 (Box-folder 109/31)
  - Picnics and other outings, Subseries 16
    - Picnics, 1891-1893 (Box-folder 109/32)
    - 4th of July church picnic in Sellwood, circa 1902 (Box-folder 109/33)
    - Picnic at Sellwood Park, 1906 (Box-folder 110/1)
    - Picnic, 1935 (Box-folder 110/2)
    - Reverend Raymond Walker at church picnic, circa 1955 (Box-folder 110/3)
    - Picnic, 1967 (Box-folder 110/4)
    - Picnics, circa 1970-2000 (Box-folder 110/5)
    - Picnic (slides), 1979 (Box-folder 110/6)
    - Picnic, 1985 August 25 (Box-folder 110/7)
    - Picnic, 2002 July (Box-folder 110/8)
    - Picnic, circa 2005 (Box-folder 110/9)
    - Picnic, 2005 July 10 (Box-folder 110/10)
    - Retreat, 1972 January (Box-folder 110/11)
    - Family retreat, 1972 October (Box-folder 110/12)
    - Retreat, circa 1983 (Box-folder 110/13)
    - Retreat, 1986 November 29 (Box-folder 110/14)
  - Receptions and talks, Subseries 17
    - Receptions, circa 1950; circa 1980-1990 (Box-folder 110/15)
    - Send-off reception for Mark Gustafson, circa 1986 (Box-folder 110/16)
    - Reception honoring Amy Rapp, 1995 August 27 (Box-folder 110/17)
    - Reception honoring 35th anniversary of Reverend Lincoln Y. Reed's ordination, 1984 September 18 (Box-folder 110/18)
    - Reception to welcome Reverend John Rogers, 1987 (Box-folder 110/19, 113/17)
    - Reception for Don and Barbara Rowland, 1987 August 9 (Box-folder 110/20)
    - Talk by James DePriest, 1986 (Box-folder 110/21)
    - Talk by architect Nancy Merriman, circa 1986 (Box-folder 110/22)
    - Oliver lectures, 1985; circa 1995 (Box-folder 110/23)
  - Church services, Subseries 18
    - Services, circa 1965, 1981-2005 (Box-folder 110/24)
    - Baptism service, 1978 March (Box-folder 110/25)
    - Christmas services, circa 1955-1965 (Box-folder 110/26)
    - Christmas services, 1971, circa 1975 (Box-folder 110/27)
    - Good Friday service, 1978 March 24 (Box-folder 113/16)
    - Service to dedicate church remodel, 1986 (Box-folder 110/28)
    - Ordination and installation services, 1960-1996 (Box-folder 110/29)
    - Photo book of Sara Rosenau's ordination service, 2013 (Box-folder 110/30)
    - Palm Sunday procession, 2002 (Box-folder 111/1)
    - Palm Sunday with Cinnamon the Donkey, 2009 (Box-folder 111/2)
      Includes enclosed thank-you card.
    - Robes and banners, 2010 (Box-folder 111/3)
      Possibly used for Easter services.
    - Service to honor Donald Sevetson for 30 years of ministry, 1988 May (Box-folder 111/4)
    - Church members dressed for Thanksgiving service, 1977 (Box-folder 111/5)
    - Thanksgiving services, circa 1985, 1988, 1990 (Box-folder 111/6)
  - Other events, Subseries 19
    - Special events, circa 1955, 1980-circa 1995 (Box-folder 111/7)
    - Appreciation dinner, 1970 June 23 (Box-folder 111/8)
    - Auction, circa 1993 (Box-folder 111/9)
    - Coffee Hour gatherings, circa 1950-1985 (Box-folder 111/10)
    - "Denominational activities" (Box-folder 111/11)
    - Elder Lamb donation party, 1896 (Box-folder 111/12, 113/10)
    - "Fun-Nite at the Pops", 1969 April 25 (Box-folder 111/13)
    - Halloween party, 1972 October (Box-folder 111/14)
    - "Hanging the Greens" event, 1971 December (Box-folder 111/15)
    - Frances McGlone's 75th birthday party, 1987 (Box-folder 111/16)
    - Mrs. Harold Rice in period costume for Oregon Centennial banquet, 1959 (Box-folder 111/17)
    - Pacific Coast Congress group photo, 1888 (Box-folder 111/18)
    - Group photo of Pacific Slope Conference attendees at First Congregational Church, 1928 (Box-folder Oversize 48)
    - Rose Festival parade float, 1955 (Box-folder 111/19)
    - Woman advertising rummage sale, 1956 (Box-folder 111/20)
    - Summer Youth Festival in Fellowship Hall, circa 1967 (Box-folder 111/21)
    - Treasure Sale, 2005 June 25 (Box-folder 111/22)
    - Unidentified event in Park Blocks, circa 1967 (Box-folder 111/23)
  - Other images, Subseries 20
    - Unbound album, 2005 (Box-folder 111/24-111/26)
      Album compiled as a promotional item for fundraising, depicting church activities in 2004 and 2005. Three copies. Copy in folder 111/26 may be closest to being in original order.
    - Portrait of Reverend C. W. Chattin, circa 1890 (Box-folder 111/27)
      Chattin was not a member of the First Congregational Church.
    - Residence of Reverend George Atkinson, circa 1870 (Box-folder 111/28)
    - Sign for church service, 1979 June (Box-folder 111/29)
    - Sketch by Jacqueline Johnson of 1854 Sunday School class, undated (Box-folder 111/30)
      Illustration based on Sophia Pratt's reminiscences, a copy of which are located in 53/26.
    - Illustration of unidentified building, undated (Box-folder 111/31)
    - Unidentified man with antique car, circa 1985 (Box-folder 111/32)
- Other materials and ephemera, 1880-2011; Series W
  - "Annual pass for good luck" card made out to Anna Chenoweth by Reverend Elwin L. House, 1906 (Box-folder 97/3)
  - Bookmark design for Fist Congregational Church Memorial Library, undated (Box-folder 97/4)
  - Bookmarks, circa 1940, undated (Box-folder 97/5)
  - Materials re Camp Adams, 1948-1992 (Box-folder 97/6)
  - Certificates awarded to First Congregational Church, 1972, 1999-2006 (Box-folder 97/7)
  - "Church Membership" booklets, 1903-1906 (Box-folder 97/8)
  - "The Congregationalist's Pilgrimage to England and Holland", 1896 (Box-folder 112/1)
  - Dedication services, 1895-1986 (Box-folder 97/9)
  - Essay by Louise Woods, 1953 October 22 (Box-folder 97/10)
  - Invitation to church picnic, circa 1898 (Box-folder 97/11)
  - Invitations to "The Gathering" events, 1985 (Box-folder 97/12)
  - Invitations to ordination services at other churches, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 97/13)
  - Japanese scroll thanking First Congregational Church, 1926 (Box-folder Oversize 49)
  - Minutes and resolution re proposed union between Pacific University and Albany College, 1916 July (Box-folder 97/14)
  - "A Normal Day at First Church", circa 1959 (Box-folder 97/15)
    Poem.
  - Plans for residence at 1212 SW Nevada Street, circa 1959 (Box-folder Oversize 50)
    House was residence of Reverend John Rogers during his tenure as senior minister.
  - Posters for Christmas services, 2011 (Box-folder 112/28)
    Posters autographed by Roger Perry.
  - Materials re principles of Congregationalism (Box-folder 97/16)
  - Programs for Christmas, Easter and Thanksgiving services, 1880, 1902, 1906 (Box-folder 97/17)
  - Program for Christmas exercises, 1899 (Box-folder 97/18)
  - Program for holiday auction, 1993 December 5 (Box-folder 97/19)
  - Program for Jefferson High School baccalaureate service at First Congregational Church, 1955 June 5 (Box-folder 97/20)
  - Programs and clippings about special services, 1940-2002 (Box-folder 97/21)
  - Program for union revival meetings, circa 1903 (Box-folder 97/22)
  - Registration cards, circa 1920 (Box-folder 97/23)
  - Research files re Harvey Clarke (Box-folder 97/24)
  - Research files re Dr. Albert Buckner Coe (Box-folder 97/25)
  - "The Rise and Progress of the Boxer Movement in China", 1900 (Box-folder 97/26)
  - Rubbing made of 1871 plaque recased in 1901, undated (Box-folder Oversize 51)
  - Page of blank stationery, 1900 (Box-folder 97/27)
  - United Boys Brigade charter, 1896 (Box-folder 155/2)
  - Welcome sign with information about church and building, circa 2003 (Box-folder 113/25)